Finding Aid for Charles E. Coughlin Sermons and Sunday Evening Radio Addresses 1930-1940
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles E. Coughlin Sermons and Sunday Evening Radio Addresses
1930-1940
Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979.
Published sermons and Sunday evening radio addresses
DA 2; C854; S486; Box
100 items approximate
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The items within the collection were received from different sources.
The collection is open for research.
Father Charles E. Coughlin was Roman Catholic priest, renowned as founder and pastor of the Shrine of the Little Flower in Royal Oak, Michigan. Father Coughlin gained a wide following for his Sunday afternoon radio addresses on political and economic subjects. Coughlin was a vocal opponent of Franklin Roosevelt and the New Deal.
The collection consists of published sermons and Sunday evening radio addresses given by Father Coughlin in the period 1930-1940. The materials are arranged chronologically.
Subjects:
Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979.; Sermons--American.
- Sermons and Sunday Evening Radio Addresses, 1930-1940
  (arranged by date)
  - Four sermons: excerpts from the Fisher Tre Ore services, undated (Box 1)
  - "Lest We Forget" Sunday, November 9, 1930 (Box 1)
  - "'The Slaughter of the Innocents"' Sunday, March 8, 1931 (Box 1)
  - "The Great Betrayal" Sunday, March 22, 1931 (Box 1)
  - The Dedication Services of the Charity Crucifixion Tower; sermon. Sunday, October 11, 1931 (Box 1)
    (Published with addresses by: Right Reverend Michael James Gallager, D.D., Bishop of Detroit; Right Reverend Joseph Schrembs, D.D., Bishop of Cleveland; Hon. Wilber M. Brucker, Governor of Michigan; Hon. Frank Murphy, Mayor of Detroit)
  - "A Sandy Foundation" Sunday, January 31, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "The Secret Is Out!" Sunday, February 14, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "The Introduction" Sunday, October 16, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "Taxation-Its Remedy" Sunday, October 23, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "Gold-Master or Servant?" Sunday, October 30, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "Revaluation" Sunday, November 6, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "Gold-The Medium of Exchange" Sunday, November 13, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "The Human Standard-Old and New" Sunday, November 20, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "Use and Not Abuse" Sunday, November 27, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "Our Solitary Boast" Sunday, December 4, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "And Opening Their Treasures, They Offered Him Gifts-Gold Incense and Myrrh" Sunday, December 18, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "The New Age" Sunday, January 1, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "Bonds or Charity?" Sunday, January 22, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "The March of the Workers" Sunday, January 29, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "The Suicide of Capitalism" Sunday, February 5, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "The Salvation of Capitalism" Sunday, February 12, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "Gold-Private or Public?" Sunday, February 19, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "Banks and Gold" Sunday, February 26, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "Lateral and Frontal Attack" Sunday, October 22, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "The New Temple" Sunday, October 29, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "The Restoration of Silver" Sunday, November 5, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "The Call to Arms" Sunday, November 12, 1933 (Box 1)
  - "Following the Christ-Child!" Sunday, December 23, 1934 (Box 1)
  - "'An Introduction'-(Keep Out of War)" Sunday, November 3, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "Our Sovereign Right and the Patman Plan" Sunday, November 10, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "Taking Inventory of My Stewardship" Sunday, November 17, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "Social Justice and Communism" Sunday, November 24, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "To Perfect and Not Destroy" Sunday, December 1, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "Forward to Victory" Sunday, December 8, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "Our First and Necessary Reform" Sunday, December 15, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "Supply and Demand-A New Year's Resolution" Sunday, December 29, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "The Bonus and Neutrality" Sunday, January 5, 1936 (Box 1)
  - "The Federal Reserve Bank Case" Sunday, January 12, 1936 (Box 1)
  - "Who are the Inflationists?" Sunday, February 9, 1936 (Box 1)
  - "Together We Stand" Sunday, January 9, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "A Permanent Cure for the Recession" Sunday, January 16, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "Shall We Enter into a League with Death?" Sunday, February 13, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "Unsound Property Laws" Sunday, February 20, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "Five Years of the New Deal" Sunday, March 6, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "The Corporative State" Sunday, March 13, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "Taxation Through Misrepresentation" Sunday, March 20, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Three Lectures on the Reorganization Bill
    - "New Deal Bookkeeping" Sunday, March 27, 1938 (Box 1)
    - "'It Is What We Do, Not What We Say'" Thursday, March 31, 1938 (Box 1)
    - "The Spirit of the Reorganization Bill" Sunday, April 3, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "Persecution-Jewish and Christian" and "Let Us Consider the Record" Sunday November 20, 1938 and Sunday, November 27, 1938 (Box 1)
  - "The President's Message to Congress" Sunday, January 8, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Rightists Go into Action" Sunday, January 15, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Ten Million Unemployed" Sunday, January 22, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Why Leave Our Own?" Sunday, January 29, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Foreign Relations-In Three Acts" Sunday, February 5, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Fides Intrepida" Sunday, February 12, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Internationalism-or No Foreign Entanglements" Sunday, February 19, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "An American Christian Program" Sunday, February 26, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Papacy-Pius VII and Pius XII" Sunday, March 5, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Bonds and Neutrality" Sunday, March 12, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Our Problem is in America" Sunday, March 26, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Foreign Aggressors" Sunday, April 16, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "So This Is Democracy!" Sunday, April 30, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Propaganda at Work" Sunday, May 7, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Policy of 'Social Justice Magazine"' and "Social Justice and Democracy" Sunday, May 21, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Memorial Day and Pentecost" Sunday, May 28, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Christians, Be Militant" Sunday, June 4, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Questions and Answers on the Visit of Their Britannic Majesties" Sunday, June 11, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The 'Neutrality' Bill" and "Billy's Rose" Sunday, June 18, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Government by Law or by Man?" Sunday, June 25, 1939 (Box 1)
  - The American Declaration of Independence and Washington's Farewell Address, as broadcast by Rev. Chas. E. Coughlin. Sunday, July 2, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Let's Have an Armed Guard" Sunday, July 9, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Appeal to the Laboring Man" Sunday, July 16, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Popular Front vs. The Christian Front" Sunday, July 30, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Unpayable Debts" Sunday, August 6, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "To the Laboring Men" Sunday, August 13, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Popular Front" Sunday, August 20, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "What of the Future?" Sunday, August 27, 1939 (Box 1)
    (Published with "The Challenge of the Pact and the Challenge of Social Justice" by Rev. Edward Lodge Curran, president of the International Catholic Truth Society)
  - "The Good Samaritan" Sunday, September 3, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "'Cash and Carry'" Sunday, September 10, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "If Cash-and-Carry, Then War Within a Year" Sunday, September 17, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The President's Message to Congress" Sunday, September 24, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Lifting the Embargo-A Victory for the Future" Sunday, October 1, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Senator William E. Borah-No Blood Profits" Sunday, October 8, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Neutrality Bill-The First Step Towards Communism" Sunday, October 15, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Lifting the Embargo Begets an Emergency; An Emergency Begets Dictatorship" Sunday, October 22, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Embargo Lifted-What of the Future?" Sunday, November 5, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Chrysler-C.I.O. Industrial Strike" Sunday, November 12, 1939 (Box 1)
    (Published with "A Statement on the Chrysler Strike," by David Brann, former secretary-treasurer of the Detroit and Wayne County District of the U.A.W.A.)
  - "The Chrysler-C.I.O. Industrial Strike" Sunday, November 19, 1939 (Box 1)
    (Published with: "A Statement on the Chrysler Strike," by David Brann; a statement by the Editor of "Social Justice" entitled "Letter on Labor and Strikes by Archbishop Francis J. L. Beckman, S.T.D., and Father Coughlin's Attitude;" and "A Complete Program," by the Editor of "Social Justice")
  - "Strikes and the National Labor Relations Board" Sunday, November 26, 1939 (Box 1)
    (Published with "America Awake" by Rev. Aubert, O.F.M., Sacred Heart Franciscan Province)
  - "The National Labor Relations Act-Its History and Proposed Amendments" Sunday, December 3, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "Recovery or Stagnation" and Our Solitary Boast" Sunday, December 10, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "India's Financial Revolt" and "A Patron for Social Justice Workers" Sunday, December 17, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "A Christmas Message" Sunday, December 24, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "A Retrospect-and a Program" and "An Examination of Conscience" Sunday, December 31, 1939 (Box 1)
  - "The Presidential Message to Congress" Sunday, January 7, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "Can Man Catch Up with the Machine?" Sunday, January 14, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "I Take My Stand" Sunday, January 21, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "I Take My Stand" and "Discussing 'A' Christian Front" Sunday, January 21-28, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "The Youth, the Citizenry and the Politician" Sunday, February 18, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "We Pause to Remember" Sunday, February 25, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "'Communism Accepts Religion'" Sunday, March 3, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "The History of Holy Week" Sunday, March 10, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "The Cross and Suffering" Sunday, March 17, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "The Story of the Resurrection" Sunday, March 24, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "Let Us Solve Our Home Problems" Sunday, March 31, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "The Birth of a Bond" Sunday, April 7, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "The Abuse of Bonds" Sunday, April 14, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "Gold and the Second World War" Sunday, April 21, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "Who Owns the Federal Reserve Banks" Sunday, April 28, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "Financial Liberty" Sunday, May 5, 1940 (Box 1)
  - "May 12, 1940" (Box 1)